Nancy Hale Papers, 1908-1989
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
A234 "What This Old Thing?" Authors Guild Bulletin. The Authors League of America, Inc. Feb. 1962: 2-4.
A235 "The Other Side of the Cove." Poetry. Vol. xcviii, n. 5. August 1961: 313-318.
A236 New England Discovery: A Personal View. Ed. Nancy Hale. New York: Coward-MacCann, 1963.
A237 Daugher of Abolitionists. Ed. Nancy Hale. Westhampton: Smith College, 1964.
A238 A New Introduction. A New England Boyhood. By Edward Everett Hale. Boston: Little Brown, 1964. v-x.
A239 "The Public Library Belongs to Us." McIntire Public Library newsletter. Charlottesville, Virginia. 1964. + +
A240 Brief Untitled Essay on Nathan Hale. This Nation: The Spirit of America in Songs,Speeches, Poems, and Documents. Cleveland: World Publishing Company, 1967. 60-61.
A241 Introduction. New England. Ed. Joe McCarthy. New York: Time-Life Library of America, 1967.
A242 "Can Writers Ignore Critics?" Saturday Review. 23 March 1968.
A243 "The Other Side of the Rotunda." Speech for University of Virginia Graduation May 1975.
A244 "Beatrice Hinkle." Dictionary of American Biography. 1976. + +
A245 "The Battle of New Market." Carry Me Back: An Anthology of Virginia Fiction. Ed. Mary MacArthur. Arlington, VA: Gallimaufry, 1978. 119-126.
A246 "The Facts of Life." Confrontation. Spring/Summer 1978. + +
A247 "Who Needs No Introduction." A Book for Boston. Eds. Llewellyn Howland and Isabelle Story. Boston: Godine, 1980. 39-44.
A248 "Miss Dugan." An Apple for My Teacher: Twelve Authors Tell about Teachers Who Made the Difference. Ed. Louis D. Rubin, Jr. Chapel Hill: Algonquin Books, 1987. 115-122.
A249 "Analyzing Fiction." N.d.
10. Translations
Listed alphabetically by country of reprint.
France:
A250 Femmes Perdues et Retrouvees (Prodigal Women). Paris: Le Rouge e Le Noir, 1949. 543 pages. Translated by Isabel Rollet.
A251 La Belle Ambitieuse ( The Sign of Jonah). Paris: Librairie Stock, 1952. 340 pages. Translated by Lola Tranec.
Germany:
A252 Nach Mir Die Sintflut (The Sign of Jonah). Hamburg: J.P. Toth Verlag, 1951. 523 Pages. Translated by Theresia Mutzenbecher.
B. Unpublished Works
Special Collections at The University of Virginia contains folders from Nancy Hale's files of both published and unpublished works. While they provide a wealth of Hale's work, many contain little identifying information. Few of the works are dated, many are untitled, and others have been given more than one title. All available identifying information is included. The entries in each section are listed alphabetically.
1. Unpublished Longer Works:
B1 All Things Come. Title replaces Two in the Bush, which replaces The Bird in Hand. Play dated 1932.
B2 Among Oak. Original title, Boston, is crossed out.
B3 Colonel Zinzindorf. Typescript of 41 pages.
B4 It's Your Dream, Perchance to Dream, A Little Night Music listed as possible titles for this play.
B5 The Princess. Typescript of 41 pages in 3 parts.
B6 The Seed of Destruction. Typescript of 50 pages.
B7 Total Love.
2. Unpublished Short Works:
B9 "Absolutely No Psychology." c. 1955. + +
B10 "Abuse." 1985. + +
B11 "The Actress We Each Are." Short story.
B12 "After the Snow." Short story.
B13 "All Things Lovely." Short story.
B14 "The American Sisters." Short story.
B15 "Another World." Short story. Originally titled "The Two Worlds."1954.
B16 "Are Philosophers People?" Short story.
B17 "Artificial Flowers." Short story.
B18 "The Artist." 1983. + +
B19 "The Artist, as an Old Bostonian." Short story.
B20 "Artists Life." 1966. + +
B21 "At Sea." 1964. + +
B22 "The Attractive Day." Short story. Pencil notation on manuscript says sold.
B23 "Autobiography." Speech.
B24 "Back to Normal." Short story.
B25 "The Battle of the Supermarket." 1977. + +
B26 "Before the Mirror." Short story.
B27 "Before the Train." Short story.
B28 "Being a Woman Writer." Book and Author Luncheon, Baltimore, MD. 1963. Speech.
B29 "Beyond the Alps Lies Italy." Short story.
B30 "The Big Laugh." Short story.
B31 "A Bit of the Real England." 1968. + +
B32 "The Boston Girl." 1970. Speech.
B33 "The Break at Dawn." Short story.
B34 "Bright Star in Darkness." + +
B35 "The Brook." Short story.
B36 "The Catalyst." Short story.
B37 "A Change of Attire." Short story.
B38 "Character." Speech.
B39 "Character and Thomas Wolfe." 1962. Speech.
B40 "The Child's Garden of the Irish." 1955. + +
B41 "A Child's World War." Short story.
B42 "The Child Within." Short story.
B43 "The Church for Me." Essay.
B44 "The Citadel." Short story.
B45 The Collaborators. Drama.
B46 "Comes the Revolution." 1934. + +
B47 "The Coming of Age." 1987. + + [highly questionable date]
B48 "Communicating and Being Communicated With." Speech.
B49 "The Consent of the Governed. 1965. + +
B50 "Content in Fiction." Speech.
B51 "Creativity." Speech.
B52 "The Crooks." Short story.
B53 "The Cruet." Short story.
B54 "Daughter of Abolitionists." 1964. + +
B55 "The Dawn Patrol." Short story.
B56 "Days Become Dear." + +
B57 "Dead March." Short story.
B58 "Death of an Artist." 1966. + +
B59 "The Death of Mr. Walter's Heart." Short story.
B60 "Defeated." Poem dated 1933.
B61 "Describing." 1984. Children's story.
B62 "The Difference. Short story.
B63 "The Discomforts of Home." Essay.
B64 "Distracted." 1977. + +
B65 "The Doctor." 1984. + +
B66 "Dog." Children's story.
B67 "The Dog Light and the Cat Light." Short story.
B68 "Eastern Point." Short story.
B69 "Emotions by God." Short story.
B70 "An End of Fiction." 1976. Speech.
B71 "England Is in the Eye of the Beholder." 1965. + +
B72 "English-Speaking Union." + +
B73 "Ensnared." 1977. + +
B74 "The Evidence." 1966. + +
B75 "Examples." Short story.
B76 "Family Groups." 1968. + +
B77 "Far Out." 1968. + +
B78 "A Fiction Writer Faces Facts." 1964. Speech.
B79 "Flannery O'Connor--Prodigal Daugher's Return." Speech.
B80 "The Flight Abroad." Short story.
B90 "The Flower Show." 1970. + +
B91 "Funny Woman." Short story.
B92 "The General's Daughter." Short story.
B93 "Getting Ideas." Speech.
B94 "Girl from the City." 1986. Children's story.
B95 "Glamor Glamor." 1976. + +
B96 "The Gods Kill Some Time." Short story.
B97 "The Great Houses." 1968. + +
B98 "The Haunted Woman." Short story.
B99 "A Haunting Gallery." Short story.
B100 "The Hidden Approach. + +
B101 "How to Keep Going Though Wretched." Essay.
B102 "Hurricane-Jacks." Short story.
B103 "Illusion." 1963. + +
B104 "In a Bedroom in the Country." + +
B105 "In a Penthouse." + +
B106 "In-Laws." 1971. + +
B107 "In Place of Calling." Short story.
B108 "Inside Tommy Boy." Children's story. 1984.
B109 "The Insult." Short story.
B110 "In the Porch." 1985. + +
B111 "In Training/Little Girls." 1976. + +
B112 "Introduction for Virginia Mishnun Hardman. Speech.
B113 "Introduction for Virginia Moore," 1977. Speech.
B114 "It Really Is." Short story.
B115 "Janey's Atom." Short story.
B116 "A Judgment." 1966. + +
B117 "To Kill a Cat." Short story.
B118 "A Lady Traveling Alone." 1961. + +
B119 "Language as a Vessel of Meaning." + +
B120 "Last Summer." Short story.
B121 "The Leap." Short story.
B122 "Let Go, Let Go." + +
B123 "A Letter Home." Short story.
B124 "A Letter to My Love. Short story.
B125 "Life for the City (?)." + + [punctuation may be Smith College's]
B126 "Likeness." 1967, + +
B127 "The Little Baron." Short story.
B128 "A Little Girl of Long Ago." 1984. + + (B89) "Little Girls." [see "In Training" above]
B129 "Little Lord Who-Am-I." Review of F.H.Burnett's Little Lord Fauntleroy. Notes on the folder label indicate that the review was written for The Georgia Review about a Scribner's publication, but it is not shown in its published form.
B130 "The Lost Summer." Children's story.
B131 "Love." Short story.
B132 "Luke." Short story.
B133 "Magic Heroes and Practical Saviours." 1972. Speech.
B134 "The Mahogany Box." Short story.
B135 "Make Friends with Your Family." Short story.
B136 "Man Stands in Need." Short story.
B137 "Mary Ann." + +
B138 "The Misercordia." Short story.
B139 "Miss Smith from Jackson City." Short story. 1939. + + [date only]
B140 "The Misses Harris." Short story.
B141 "Monster." Short story. [Smith College notes: Red Book? and 1939]
B142 "Mortality." Short story.
B143 "Mother." Short story.
B144 "Mr. McPharlane." Short story.
B145 "Mr. Robbin" or "Mr. Robbins." Short story.
B146 "Mrs. Stanislas: by Sargent." Short story.
B147 "Mutual Friends." 1926. + +
B148 "My Sister Kate." Short story. c. 1954 + + [date only]
B149 "A New Day." Short story.
B150 "A New Life." Short story.
B151 "No Accounting for Tastes." Short story.
B152 "No Work for Ladies." Short story.
B153 "Not Solomon." Short story.
B 154 Novel vs. Short Story. [title taken from content] Speech.
B155 "Of Giving Many Dinners. Short story.
B156 "Old Stuff." Short story.
B157 "O Mason All to Thee." Short story.
B158 "One Touch of Malice." Short story.
B159 "Open Sesame." +
B160 "Other People's Lives." 1961? + +
B161 "O True Apothecary!" 1934. + +
B162 "Painted Into a U-Corner." Essay. 14 September 1956. + + [date only]
B163 "A Party of Four." Short story.
B164 "Persephone." Short story. c. 1954. + + [date only]
B165 "The Petals of the Flower." Short story.
B166 "Pie." Children's story.
B167 "Pink and White Cake." Short story.
B168 "The Place and the Time." Short story.
B169 "This Place and Wherever You are." Short story. 1961. + + [date only]
B170 "The Poet." Short story.
B171 "The Presence of Children." 1966. + +
B172 "Raccoon Is Back." Children's story. 1985.
B173 "A Real Good Time." 1966. + +
B174 "The Reality." Short story.
B175 "Recovery." Short story.
B176 "Remembering." 1978. + +
B177 "The Return." Poem.
B178 "Room for a Baby." Short story.
B179 "Roots" or "Station in Life." + +
B180 "Rosie and Jinny and Jim." Short story.
B181 "The Rusted House." Short story.
B182 "Sailing Lessons." + +
B183 "The Search for New England." 1977. + +
B184 "Seeing." 1971. + +
B185 "Self-made Cinderella." Short story.
B186 "The Sheltered One." Short story.
B187 "A Short Story." Short story.
B188 "Silver-Spoon Trouble." Short story.
B189 "The Sisters." Short story.
B190 "The Skeptical Shepherd." Short story.
B191 "The Slave." Short story.
B192 "Sing a Song of Psyche." Poem.
B193 "Some Day I'll Find You." Short story.
B194 "Souvenir of Dr. Grady." Short story.
B195 "Station in Life" or "Roots." + +
B196 "A Story." Short story. + +
B197 "The Story of Jean Strecker." Short story.
B198 "The Story of Rory." Children's Story. 1985. + +
B199 "The Strange Case of Mr. Biddle." Short story.
B200 "A Strange House." Childrens' story. 1984. + +
B201 "St. Valentine's Coming!" 1984. + +
B202 "The Summertime." Short story.
B203 "The Summer Without the Raccoon." Children's story. 1985. + +
B204 "The Taming of Miss Shrewsbury." Short story.
B205 "Tampering with Mr. Wodehouse." Short story.
B206 "Tea Party." Children's Story. 1986. + +
B207 "The Tide." +
B208 "The Toast of New York." Short story.
B209 "To Eleanor Wylie." Essay.
B210 "Too Many Doctors." Short story.
B211 "To Those Who Sit in Darkness." Short story.
B212 "The Trap." 1985. + +
B213 "Treasure." 1969. + +
B214 "The Troubles of Elizabeth." Children's story. 1984. + +
B215 "Trust." Children's Story. 1986.
B216 "The Ultimate Valentine." Short story. 1954. + + [date only]
B217 Untitled address on the subject of creative writing. Essay.
B218 Untitled address about the problems of the short story writer. Essay.
B219 Untitled sketch of University of Virginia Hospital. Essay.
B220 "The Village." 1977. + +
B221 "Violation." Short story.
B222 "Violet." Short story.
B223 "Vogue's Eye-View of the Mode." Two paragraphs. Undated and unsigned.
B224 "The Wages of Whoopee." Short story.
B225 "The Warm Coat." Short story.
B226 "The Way of Dreams." Short story.
B227 "Weeping Alexanders." Short story.
B228 "What God Was Writing." Essay.
B229 "What Makes A Memory Unforgettable." Essay.
B230 "Where Is My Father." Short story.
B231 "Why Do They Do It?" Macdowell Colony. 1977. + +
B232 "Why Hearest Thou Music Sadly?" + +
B233 "Why Nobody Came." Short story.
B234 "The Wild Boy of Carl Shurtz Park." Short story.
B235 "The Wings." Short story.
B236 "With Brief Thanksgiving." Short story.
B237 "The World Outside." 1968. + +
B238 "A Yankee's Disillusionment." Short story.
B239 "Young." 1977. + +
B240 "The Young Girl." Short story.
B241 "The Young Lochinvar and the Tragic Muse." Short story.
B242 "Young Men of Affairs." Short story.
3.Fragments and Untitled Works: Listed by title when available, or subject or opening phrase
B243 Progress report on stroke. + + In Box 9 of Nancy Hale papers in Special Collections, University of Virginia:
B244 "This is the University Hospital…" Untitled essay.
B245 Address on creative writing.
B246 Address on the problems of the short story writer, given to Colonnade Club.
B247 "Susie Parsons, my neighbor, may not be beautiful…" Short story. In Box 10 of Nancy Hale papers in Special Collections, University of Virginia:
B248 Group of poems.
C. Secondary Sources:
1. Selected Writings about Hale:
C1 Schorer, Mark. Yale Review. Summer 1943.
C2 New Republic. 12 July 1943.
C3 Gelder, Robert van. "Nancy Hale…An Analyzer of the Feminine," in his Writers and Writing. New York: Scribners, 1946. 330-333.
C4 "Distinguished Author Summers at Folly Cove: Nancy Hale, Descendent of Edward Everett Hale, Here Revising Proofs of New Book." Gloucester Daily Times. 11 July 1950.
C5 Omwake, John. "A Writer Speaks Out on Her Craft." The Cavalier Daily. University of Virginia. 12 Dec. 1963.
C6 Simmonds, Anne. "A Profile of a Lioness of Letters."The Daily Progress. 9 June 1966. 6.
C7 "Art of 'How to Take Criticism' to Be Discussed by Author Today." Richmond News Leader. 10 Jan. 1968. *
C8 Ellyson, Louise. "Author Claims Criticism Harmed Bronte, Wolfe." Richmond Times-Dispatch. 11 Jan. 1968. C-2.
C9 Coffey, Shelby III. "Fugitive Sophisticate: The New Yorker and Nancy Hale." The Washington Post (Potomac). 24 Nov. 1968. 25, 16.
C10 Berg, A. Scott. Max Perkins, Editor of Genius. New York: Dutton, 1978. 206, 402-403,413.
C11 Wheelock, John Hall, ed. The Letters of Maxwell Perkins. New York: Scribners, 1979. 126-127, 191, 209-210.
C12 Kamholz, Doug. "Writing Careers for Charlottesville Couple are a Natural," Charlottesville Daily Progress. 18 November 1979. E1, E8.
C13 Wilcox, Ned. "Hale and Bowers: A Marriage of Two Minds," University of Virginia Cavalier Daily. 18 November 1979. 3.
C14 Richardson, Anne. "Nancy Hale Gives Up Short Stories--For Now." Daily Progress. 3 Aug. 1980.
C15 Battestin, Ruthe. "Dedication, Nancy Hale," in Our Community & the Arts, Charlottesville Daily Progress. 23 September 1980. 6-7.
C16 Freeman, Anne Hobson. "Nancy Hale." Dictionary of Literary Biography Yearbook: 1980. Eds. Karen L. Rood, Jean W. Ross, and Richard Ziegfeld. Detroit: Gale, 1981. 212-219.
C17 Buchanan, Laurie. "Nancy Hale". American Short Story Writers 1910-1945: First Series. Dictionary of Literary Biography. Ed. Bobby Ellen Kimbel. Vol. 86. Detroit: Gale, 1989. 124-129
C18 Freeman, Anne Hobson. "Nancy Hale (6 May 1908-24 September 1988)." Dictionary of Literary Biography Yearbook: 1988. Ed. J.M. Brook. Detroit: Gale, 1989. 218-228.
C19 "Nancy Hale." American National Biography. New York: Oxford UP, 1998.
2. Selected Reviews of Hale's Works: Reviews are organized chronologically under the works represented, which are ordered alphabetically. Many of the reviews were collected by clip agencies for the publisher, who forwarded them to Hale. The files at the University of Virginia hold the majority of these reviews. All available information is listed. The clipped reviews provide no page numbers for the publication.
The Best of Everything:
C20 "Opening-Night Audience Sees Nancy Hale's Play," The Daily Progress. 8 May 1952.
C21 Jennes, Ernie. The Progress-Index. Petersburg, VA. 17 October 1952: 17.
C22 Review. The Hopewell News. 17 October 1952.
C23 Review. The Daily Progress. 12 May 1953.
Between the Dark and the Daylight:
C24 *. "Nancy Hale's Subtle Sketches." Tribune.
C25 Molloy, Robert. "The Book of the Day." Article from Associated Press.
C26 Welty, Eudora. "Women and Children," New York Times Book Review. 2 May 1943: 8.
The Earliest Dreams
C27 Chase, Jane. "Tenderness and Insight in Nancy Hale's Sketches." Minneapolis Star.
C28 "Emotional Hi-lights by an Expert." Sioux City Tribune.
C29 "Nancy Hale Writes New Short Series: Unhappiness Is Theme in Her Latest Collection." Minneapolis Journal.
C30 Young, Viola. "Earliest Dreams." Denver News.
C31 "The Younger Generation." Washington Times.
C32 Walton, Edith H. " 'The Earliest Dreams' and Other Recent *." The New York Times Book Review. April 1*. 6.
C33 Pflock, Ernst. "Bookworm's Eye-Views. West Virginian. 6 Apr. 1936.
C34 Gelder, Robert Van. "Books of the Times." New York Times. 9 Apr. 1936. L19.
C35 Hansen, Harry. "The First Reader. New York World-Telegram. 9 Apr. 1936. Reprinted in Greensboro News. 11 Apr. 1936. Reprinted in New Bedford Mercury. 11 Apr. 1936. Reprinted in Providence News-Tribune. 11 Apr. 1936. Reprinted in Norfolk Virginian Pilot. 17 Apr. 1936. Reprinted in Youngstown OH Telegram. 20 June 1936.
C36 Wood, A.L.S. "Books of the Moment." Springfield, Mass. Evening Union. 10 Apr. 1936.
C37 Gannett, Lewis. "Books and Things." New York Herald-Tribune. 11Apr. 1936. Reprinted in Charleston, WV Mail. 15 Apr. 1936.
C38 Soskin, William. "Nancy Haile's [sic] Growing Literary Artistry: Her Short Stories Reveal a Rare Warm Talent Which Follows the Tradition of Chekov." New York Herald Tribune Books. 12 Apr. 1936. VII 5.
C39 Zwart, Elizabeth Clarkson. "Nancy Hale Does a Swell Job of Story-Telling." Des Moines Register. 12 Apr. 1936. 11.
C40 Shaw, Jr., Tom. "Book-Slants." Greensboro Record. 15 Apr. 1936.
C41 Benet, William Rose. "Nancy Hale's Stories." The Saturday Review. 18 Apr. 1936.
C42 "The Earliest Dreams." Columbus Citizen. 18 Apr. 1936.
C43 "The Earliest Dreams." Durham Herald Sun. 19 Apr. 1936.
C44 "Nancy Hale's Stories Have Tragic Themes." The Springfield Republican. 19 April 1936.
C45 Walton, Edith H. "The Earliest Dreams" New York Times. 19 Apr. 1936.
C46 Wright, Monica Dempsey. "Today's Book." Macon Telegraph. 20 Apr. 1936. Chicago Herald-Examiner. 23 April 1936.
C47 Culver, Rae. "Books in the News." Rochester Journal. 23 Apr. 1936.
C48 "Delightful Humor Found in Hale's Stories." Buffalo News. 23 Apr. 1936.
C49 Lane, Arthur F. "Readers and Writers." Lyndhurst Leader. Reprinted in Rutherford Reputation.
C50 Los Angeles Examiner. 23 Apr. 1936.
C51 Brackbill, Hervey. "Nancy Hale's Skill *." Baltimore Sun. 25 Apr. 1936.
C52 McCortt. "Salt to Taste." Middleboro KY News. 25 Apr. 1936.
C53 "Unusual Short Stories." Keene NH Sentinel. 25 Apr. 1936.
C54 Clai*, John. "Heralding the*." Boston Herald. 29 Apr. 1936.
C55 Towne, Charles Hanson. "Book A Day." Washington Herald. 29 Apr. 1936.
C56 "Hale, Nancy (Mrs. T.S. Hardin)." Book Review Digest. May 1936.
C57 Andrews, Kenneth. "A Child of Chekov!" Rockefeller Center Weekly. 1 May 1936. 4.
C58 Ahlers, Margaret Ann. "Well-Told Group of Short Stories." Dayton, Ohio Journal. 9 May 1936.
C59 "Facile But Not Light Book of Short Stories." St. Louis Globe Democrat. 9 May 1936.
C60 "The Younger Generation" Winnipeg Free Press. 9 May 1936.
C61 "Book of Short Stories: Nancy Hale Reveals Much of Herself in he Collection." St. Joseph, MO News-Press. 10 May 1936.
C62 Lutz, Mark. "Nancy Hale of Artistic Age in 'The Earliest Dreams.'" The Richmond News Leader. 15 May 1936. 6.
C63 Daniel, Frank. "The Earliest Dreams." Atlanta Journal. 17 May 1936.
C64 Purdy, Ken W. "Rich Achievement." Wisconsin State Journal. 17 May 1936.
C65 Dayton News. 22 May 1936.
C66 "Note of Pathos in Nancy Hale's Short Stories." Galveston Tribune. 22 May 1936.
C67 "Earliest Dreams." New Orleans Times-Picayune. 24 May 1936.
C68 "The Earliest Dreams." Indianapolis News. 30 May 1936.
C69 "Short Stories That Are Alive." Houston Post. 31 May 1936.
C70 "Nancy Hale at Her Best." Worcester Telegram. 14 June 1936.
C71 "Shorter Notices." The Nation. 4 July 1936.
C72 Carver, Charles H. "Short Story Art By Nancy Hale." Rochester Democrat and Chronicle. 19 July 1936.
C73 Hudson, Katherine. "The Earliest Dreamland." Daily Oklahoman. 16 Aug. 1936.
C74 Jones, E.B.C. "Short Stories." The Spectator. 11 June 1937. 1114.
The Empress's Ring:
C75 Bradenburg, Alice S. "Virginian Writes Personalized Stories." Richmond Virginia News-Leader. 23 Aug. 1955.
C76 Peterson, Virgilia. "Nancy Hale's Stories, Revelations of the Troubled Heart. Herald Tribune. 14 Aug. 1955. 3.
C77 Du Bois, William. "Books of the Times." The New York Times. 13 Aug. 1955. C11.
C78 Kelly, James. "Moments of Insight." The New York Times. 14 Aug. 1955. 5
C79 Sullivan, Richard. "24 Short Stories, Bright, Fresh."
C80 White, Ellington. "Miss Hale Has Keen Insight." Richmond Times Dispatch. 28 Aug. 1955.
The Life in the Studio:
C81 Sarton, May. "The Life in the Studio." The New York Times Book Review. 27 July 1969. 7, 16.
C82 Changing Times. 34. October 1980: 84.
Mary Cassatt:
C83 Publishers Weekly. 231. 27 February 1987: 160.
A New England Discovery:
C84 Harper's Magazine. June 1960: 105.
A New England Girlhood:
C85 Poore, Charles. The New York Times. 22 May 1958. Np.
C86 Harper's Magazine. June 1958: 82-90.
C87 Times Literary Supplement. 5 December 1958: 699.
The Night of the Hurricane:
C88 Publishers Weekly. 213. 17 April 1978: 75.
C89 School Library Journal. 25. November1978: 63.
The Prodigal Women:
C90 Harper's Magazine. November 1942: 7-16.
C91 The American Spectator. 22. 12. December 1989: 29.
C92 Renyi, Judith. Philadelphia Magazine. 80. 8. August 1989: 67.
Realities of Fiction:
C93 Bower, Warren. Saturday Review (Washington, D.C.) 15 December 1962: 25-6.
Secrets: C94 Unsigned by John C. Coleman. Virginia Quarterly Review. 47. Summer 1970): xcvii.
C95 Connors, Joyce. "A Wistful View of Gracious Life," Richmond Times Dispatch. 4 April 1971.
The Sign of Jonah:
C96 Bullock, Florence Haxton. "Glamour Girl, 1928 et Seq." New York Herald Tribune. 3K.
C97 Sierer, Helen. "Sampling the New Fiction." Richmond Times Dispatch. *.
C98 Bartlett, Paul. "Nancy Shoots Stinging Arrow." Los Angeles Daily News. 11 Nov. 1950.
C99 "Cousins Knew What They Wanted--the Same Man." Indianapolis, Ind. News. 14 Oct. 1950.
C100 Schureman, Gloria. "Domineering Woman." Newark News. Oct. 1950.
C101 Irving, Margaret. "Glazed World of Fashion. Worcester, MA Telegram. 1 Oct. 1950.
C102 Campbell, Mary Ann. "More for Women." Oregon Journal. 8 Oct. 1950.
C103 Lawrence, Josephine. "The Will to Reform." Saturday Review of Literature. 14 Oct. 1950.
C104 Castel, Jack. "Beauty Sins, Suffers in 'The Sign of Jonah.'" Rocky Mountain News. 15 Oct. 1950. A 12.
C105 DuBois, Elizabeth. "Nancy Hale's Novel Is Rich, Varied." Rapid City, SD Journal. 15 Oct. 1950.
C106 "Incredibly Bad, It'll Likely Sell." Dallas Texas Times Herald. 15 Oct. 1950.
C107 Janeway, Elizabeth. "Caricatures." New York Times. 15 Oct. 1950.
C108 "The Sign of Jonah." Cleveland Ohio Plain Dealer. 15 Oct. 1950.
C109 "The Sign of Jonah." Dallas Texas News. 15 Oct. 1950.
C110 MacGregor, Martha. "Southern Beauty's Success Story." New York, NY Post Home News. 15 Oct. 1950.
C111 Starkey, Marion L. "Poisonous Glamour Girl: Nancy Hale's Latest Novel about Really Vicious Character." Morning Globe (Boston). 15 Oct. 1950.
C112 Howe, Mary Burke. "Fate Catches Up." America. 21 Oct. 1950. 82-83.
C113 Sain, Bob. " '…and There Shall Be No Sign'--'Evil and Adulterous Generation' Is Subject of Readable New Novel." Charlotte NC News. 21 Oct. 1950.
C114 Stix, Frederick W. Cincinnati Enquirer. 21 Oct. 1950.
C115 Lawrence, Henry H. "Nancy Hale Writes Swift, Sharp Novel." San Antonio Express. 22 Oct. 1950.
C116 McGrory, Mary. "Nancy Hale Writes a Powerful Novel Against a Bitter Racial Background." The Sunday Star (Washington, D.C.). 22 Oct. 1950.
C117 Rodriguez, J.S. "A Modern Love Story." Montreal, Canada Gazette. 22 Oct. 1950.
C118 "The Sign of Jonah." Providence Journal. 22 Oct. 1950.